（ヤサコ）都市伝説によると
電脳ペットは死んだあと―
According to urban legends,
after they die, cyberpets go live somewhere else.
ある場所に移り住むそうです
（メガばあ）４４２３は
イサコの患者ナンバーじゃ
4-4-2-3 is Isako's patient number!
彼女の治療のために
設置された―
The experimental Space created for Isako's cybercure,
実験医療空間
４４２３が
4-4-2-3, is the original model for "the other side."
あっちの原型なのじゃ
それに
信彦(のぶひこ)が死んだのは
Moreover, Nobuhiko didn't die because Isako made a wish to Michiko.
イサコがミチコに
願ったからではない
（オバちゃん）どういうこと？
What do you mean?
（メガばあ）信彦は交通事故の直後
すでに死んでおったのじゃ
Nobuhiko had already died in the car accident!
事故のあと かろうじて
目覚めた彼女は
When she finally awakened after the accident,
兄を失ったことを知って
再び意識を閉ざした
she learned of her brother's death and lost consciousness once again.
その心の傷を
癒やすために―
In order to relieve her broken heart, a Space was created.
作られた空間
心を埋めるものを
イマーゴを通じて―
A Space that uses the Imago to create cybersubstances
電脳物質の形で
生み出す空間
that fill the gap in a person's heart.
そう
失った兄の姿までも…
Right, even including the illusion of a dead brother.
しかし なんらかの
原因で変質し
However, for some reason, the Space degenerated...
ついには停止した
In the end, it ceased to exist,
治療中の天沢(あまさわ)勇子(ゆうこ)と―
along with Amasawa, who was still in treatment,
彼女の生み出した
心の世界とともに
and the world born inside her heart.
じゃあ 小此木(おこのぎ)医師が
手術したっていうのは…
So, the procedure that Dr. Okonogi created...
（メガばあ）そう 唯一
電脳コイルシステムを知るおじじが
Exactly, only Grandpa knew about the Dennou Coil system.
彼女を救うために
ヌル･キャリアで意識を分離させ
So, in order to save her,
he split his own consciousness,
医療空間に入り込んだのじゃ
and entered the healing Space via the Null Carrier.
そして 彼女は戻ってきた
And then she came back.
じゃが…
However...
（イサコの叔父）小此木先生は
そのまま戻られませんでした
Dr. Okonogi never came back.
先生が勇子を救ってくだすった
He saved Yuko,
ご自身の体を省みずに…
at the cost of his own life.
（メガばあ）
資料によるとイマーゴは
大人にはうまく適合せん
According to the data, adults aren't very compatible with the Imago.
負荷がかかった
おじじの体は―
Grandpa's body, already badly strained,
分離しただけで
力尽きてしもうた
exhausted its strength while still split.
（ヤサコ）
ここから先は覚えてないわ
I don't remember what happened after that.
（メガばあ）実験空間は人知れず
The experimental Space changed over time into an abnormal Space called "the other side."
あっちと呼ばれる
異空間に変容を遂げていった
4-4...
2-3.
その後 しばらく
おじじの意識は―
Brother?
Ever since then, I guess Grandpa's consciousness has wandered around "the other side"...
あっちを
さまよっていたことじゃろう
I'm looking for 4-4-2-3.
４４２３ 天沢勇子を捜し求めてな
looking for 4-4-2-3, alias Yuko Okonogi.
（ヌル）私ハ 小此木
I'm...
Okonogi.
（幼少のヤサコ）私と同じ名前だ
That's the same as my family name.
Yu... ko?
おじじ？
Grandpa!
優子
Yu... ko.
優子じゃないか！
Now that's my Yuko!
おじじ！　おじじだ～！
Grandpa!
It's Grandpa!
（幼少のヤサコ）
おじじは死んだんだよ ぽっくり
But Grandpa's dead.
Suddenly.
ほおっ 思い出した
Oh! I remember!
わしは こないだ死んだんじゃ
I died the other day!
私 あっちで
おじじと会ってたんだ
So on "the other side," I met Grandpa!
（幼少のヤサコ）
デンスケについてきたら
ここに来ちゃったの
I was following Densuke, and ended up here.
（おじじ）そうか
I see.
That's because Densuke was part of this treatment area.
デンスケも
この治療施設の一部だったからな
えっ？　そうだったんだ
So that's how things were!
さっき４４２３に会ったよ
You know, I just met 4-4-2-3.
でも女の子じゃなかった
But he wasn't a girl.
それに暗くなって消えちゃったの
And then, it became dark and he disappeared.
そうか どこにいるか分かるかい？
Really?
Any clue about where he might be?
Nope.
まあええ
Oh, whatever.
さあ もうこんなことが
起こらんように―
I gotta put a lock on to make sure things like this don't happen anymore.
鍵をかけねばな
かける前に死んでしまったんじゃ
I died before I could lock it.
（おじじ）
帰り道はデンスケが知っておる
Densuke knows the way back.
（おじじ）さあ デンスケ
孫のボディーガードになっておくれ
Come on, Densuke,
be my granddaughter's bodyguard for a while.
（おじじ）さあ 行くんだ
Go on then.
おじじ？
Grandpa?
（おじじ）さあ デンスケとお行き
Go on, go with Densuke.
そして 首輪をかけて
全部 忘れるんだ
And then put the collar on him and forget about all this.
おじじ 一緒に帰ろう！
Grandpa! Let's go back together!
（おじじ）お行き
Go.
わしは迎えに行かねばならん子が
いるんじゃよ
I must go and meet a certain child.
おじじ！
Grandpa!
おじじ…
Grandpa.
あなた さっきの？
You're... the one from just now?
Haraken!
ハラケン！
イリーガル… じゃない
An Illegal?
No, it's not.
ハッ… デンスケ？
Densuke?
ワン！
デンスケ！
Densuke!
ク～ン…
デンスケ…
Densuke...
I missed you!
会いたかった
You're warm!
あったかい　フフ フフフ…
Densuke's fur is so...
デンスケの毛並み
フサフサだったんだね
fluffy.
You're warm.
あったかい
あっ デンスケ？
Densuke?
デンスケ…
Densuke...
Is this our farewell?
お別れなの？
ク～ン…
Densuke!
デンスケ ありがとう！
Thank you!
Really,
今まで本当にありがとう
thank you for everything.
Goodbye...
さようなら デンスケ
Densuke.
Yasako!
（ハラケン）ヤサコ！
（ヤサコ）ハッ…
Yasako!
Aunty, Yasako is...
オバちゃん ヤサコが…
Yasako.
（オバちゃん）ヤサコ！
Aunty.
オバちゃん ハラケン…
Haraken.
But how could you...
一体どうやって？
Densuke
デンスケが案内してくれたの
guided me.
Densuke?
デンスケが？
He was all black, but...
真っ黒になってたけど
毛並みがフカフカだったよ
his fur was soft and fluffy!
I was able to say goodbye.
さよならが言えたよ
I won't allow it.
（ミチコ）許さない
Amasawa...
天沢さん…
ハッ… 大黒市(だいこくし)に連れてって！
Take me to Daikoku City!
Pronto!
今すぐ！
What about her cyberbody?
電脳体は？
Not yet!
まだじゃ… しかし
なぜか一部が戻り始めておる
But a part has mysteriously started to come back!
So, will Amasawa...
（ヤサコ）じゃあ 天沢さんは？
I don't know yet.
（メガばあ）まだ分からん
Then what can we do?
（オバちゃん）
じゃあ どうするのよ？
（メガばあ）うむ…
こんなこともあろうかと思って
I thought something like this could happen.
I'm gonna use my ace in the hole.
切り札に連絡済みじゃ
Ace in the hole?
切り札？
げっ！　バ… バイクが
Vehicle Removed for Parking Violation
M-My motorbike!
Geez!
しまった…
Get in!
（一郎(いちろう)）乗るんだ
Supervisor?
室長？
Supervisor,
（オバちゃん）室長
こんなことになってすみません
I'm sorry about all this.
But...
でも 娘さんの
やろうとしていることは決して…
what your daughter wanted to do is in no way...
In the cyberpocket in back, you'll find a metatag.
（一郎）後部の電脳ポシェットに
メタタグが入っている
A metatag?
メタタグ？
It's this one...
（ハラケン）これだ
That's a Coil Tag.
コイルタグだ！
ちょ… なんで こんなもの？
Why do you have this?
It's not an original.
（一郎）本物じゃない
僕の技術では再現できなかった
I wasn't able to reproduce it with my technique,
but it will work as a makeshift solution.
でも 対症療法くらいにはなる
Dad?
お… お父さん？
Yuko, I'm sorry I couldn't be by your side at a moment like this.
優子 こんなときに
近くにいてやれなくてすまなかった
Supervisor... don't tell me you are...
室長 あんた まさか…
I'm member number one.
会員番号１番だ
（ハラケン･オバちゃん）
あっ コイル探偵局のバッジ！
Ah, the Coil Investigation badge!
My mom...
（一郎）おふくろには
いろいろ弱みを握られていてな
forced me into it with threats.
I knew it had to be a trick like that!
やはり その手口か
Not only that, you should know that for the last six months,
それだけじゃない
実は半年ほど前から
メガマス本社の要請で―
at the request of the Megamass head office, I've been helping out with an internal audit.
内部監査を手伝っていたんだ
（メガばあ）んん… それにしても
一体 どこからリンクが？
But still, I wonder just where this link is...
（モジョ）モジョ
You fiends!
曲者！
うっ… この！
Take this!
うぬっ！　リンクが…
The link is...
This is an old-school encode!
これは古流の暗号か？
Even inside Megamass, there is a faction of former Coil employees.
（一郎）メガマス内部にも
旧コイルスとつながった一派がいる
They have someone working on recovering lost Coil techniques.
彼らはある男を動かして
失われたコイルスの技術を
手に入れようとしている
And who on earth is this person?
（オバちゃん）
それは 一体 何者なの？
Do you know the name of Coil's now missing master engineer?
失踪したコイルス主任技師の
名前を知っているか？
うむ この癖 この暗号の組み方…
This style...
This way of compiling the encode...
Maybe it's
もしや 会員番号３番 猫目(ねこめ)か？
member number three,
Nekome?!
The engineer's name was...
（一郎）その技師の名は猫目
Nekome.
What?
なんですって？
Sosuke Nekome is the son of the deceased engineer.
猫目宗助(そうすけ)は
失踪した技師の息子だ
Long time no see, Mega-baa.
（猫目）お久しぶりです メガばあ
Sosuke...
宗助 お主 何をたくらんでおる？
What'cha plotting?!
I'm not plotting anything.
（猫目）何もたくらんでなどいない
My goal is the same as before.
僕の目標は あの頃と同じだ
I remembered everything.
全て思い出したわい
You wanna get revenge against Megamass!
メガマスに復讐(ふくしゅう)する気なのじゃな？
Yeah,
ああ 報いを受けさせてやる
I'll make them pay through the nose.
４年前も お主が
玉子(たまこ)をそそのかしたばかりに…
I remembered that four years ago, it was all your fault. You put Tamako up to it.
わしが止めなければ―
If I hadn't stopped her,
玉子があっちに行っていたの
かもしれぬのじゃぞ！
she would've ended up on "the other side"!
（一郎）
彼は旧コイルス一派と組んで
He joined the faction of former Coil personnel,
イマーゴを軸に
本社を脅す気だったんだろう
probably intending to threaten the head office about the Imago.
（オバちゃん）
まさか カンナの事故も？
Do you mean that Kanna's accident also...
いや 原因は イマーゴと
古い空間によって起こった―
Nope, that was a navi malfunction caused by the Imago and obsolete Space.
ナビの誤動作だ
Thanks to Ken'ichi's data, we managed to prove it.
研一(けんいち)君のデータが
それを裏付けたよ
ホントですか？
Really?
（一郎）ああ
本社にも不具合の公表を確約させた
Yeah, I made the head office promise to announce the fault officially.
カンナ君には
なんの落ち度もない
Kanna was not responsible for that.
研一君
みんなの誤解を一緒に解こう
Ken'ichi,
let's resolve everyone's misunderstandings together.
は… はい
Y-Yes!
ハラケン よかった
（ハラケン）うん
Haraken, that's great.
Yes!
天沢さんも… カンナを
自分が巻き込んだんじゃないかと
Amasawa was troubled by her belief that she was responsible for involving Kanna.
気に病んでいたわ
大黒市内に入るぞ
We're entering Daikoku City!
（ヤサコ）天沢さんのお兄さんが？
Amasawa's brother?!
（オバちゃん）そう
亡くなったのは交通事故よ
Yes.
He died in a car accident.
５年前のね
Five years ago.
I gotta tell Amasawa about this.
天沢さんに伝えないと…
ああっ…
（モジョ）モジョ！
Mojo!
んんっ… もう持たん！
I can't... hold out anymore!
なんじゃ？
Wha...
（猫目）これは なんだ？
なぜ はじかれる？
What is... this?
Why is it being repelled?
まさか… タケル！
Don't tell me...
Takeru!
（ヤサコ）あっ タケル君
Takeru.
（タケル）兄ちゃんのラインは
全て はじいたよ
I repelled all of my brother's attacks.
もうこれ以上
ヒドいことはしないで！
Don't do awful things anymore!
What are you talking about?
（猫目）何を言うんだ？
この実験データが残れば
父さんの功績は世界に…
With this experimental data, we can demonstrate Dad's achievements to the world!
そんなの
父ちゃんが喜ぶわけがない
There's no way Dad would be happy about that!
父ちゃんは
イマーゴや電脳ペットを…
Dad created Imago and cyberpets...
人の心を治すために作ったんだ！
to heal people's minds!
タケル君
Takeru...
ヤサコ 今まで黙っててごめん
Yasako,
I'm sorry I never told you.
（猫目）やめろ タケル！
Stop it,
Takeru!
何を… したの？
What
did you do?
兄ちゃんのメガネを壊した
I broke my brother's glasses.
小さい頃 父ちゃんからもらった
パスワードなんだ
It's a password Dad gave me when I was very little.
タケル君
Takeru...
More important than that, Yasako!
そんなことより ヤサコ
早く天沢を呼び戻すんだ！
You gotta call Isako back home!
Yeah!
（メガばあ）
だいぶダメージを受けた
リンクが遠のいておる
She's taken quite a lot of damage.
The link is fading more and more.
What's the destination of this link?
なんなの？　このリンク先
コイルドメインに似てるけど
It looks like the Coil Domain, but...
I guess it's a mental Space just like "the other side."
（メガばあ）恐らく あっちと
同じ種類の精神空間じゃろう
しかし 今までいた空間とも違う
But it's different from the Space where she's been till now.
（オバちゃん）
正体が分からなくては
修復できないわ
If we don't understand its nature, we can't repair it!
（メガばあ）
さっき リンクがつながりかけて
Just as the link made the connection,
急に苦しそうな顔になったのじゃ
she got a pained expression.
苦しそうな顔？
A pained... expression?
痛み…
Pain...
こっち… こっちよ 天沢さん！
Here...
Come here, Amasawa!
私の声を聞いて！
Listen to my voice!
天沢さん こっちを見て！
Amasawa!
Look here!
天沢さん！
ううっ…
（ハラケン）ヤサコ！
Yasako!
これ 夢の…
This
was in my dream.
夕焼け？
The evening gloom!
Yasako!
ヤサコ！
これは分離ではない
She hasn't shifted.
リンク先は… 内側？
The link's destination is...
inside?
（信彦）どうやって接続したの？
How did you connect here?
ここには
特別な子供しか入れないんだよ
Only special kids can enter here.
（ヤサコ）ここは どこなの？
What is this place?
This is a Space created for a certain girl.
（信彦）ある女の子のために
作られた空間なんだ
傷が癒えるまで いつまでも
子供のままでいられる場所
A place where she can continue to be a child until she's healed.
僕は もうすぐいなくなるんだ
この空間と一緒にね
You know, I'm gonna be leaving soon.
Together with this Space.
いなくなるって？
Leaving?
（信彦）その女の子は
もう僕の力を借りてはいけないんだ
That girl
can't rely on my strength anymore.
そういう決まりなんだ
It's the rule.
My role will soon be over.
僕の役目は もうすぐ終わる
（鳴き声）
（ヤサコ）デンスケ！
Densuke!
（信彦）ヤサコ
Yasako.
（信彦）この犬のあとを
ついてきたんだね
So you arrived here by following this dog, huh?
どうりで…
It means that...
（ヤサコ）４４２３は
ここで何をしてるの？
What are you doing here, 4-4-2-3?
（信彦）僕は その女の子の
治療をしているんだ
I'm healing that girl.
心のね
Healing her heart.
（ヤサコ）お医者さんなの？
Are you a doctor?
（信彦）ああ そうだね
Yeah, you could say that.
君はイマーゴがあるんだね
So you have the Imago.
Then, you'd better go home now.
なら もう帰ったほうがいい
この空間は
君のような子に反応してしまう
This Space reacts to kids like you.
（ヤサコ）逃げて ２人とも！
Run!
Both of you!
（ミチコ）
やめて！　お兄ちゃんを取らないで
Stop!
Don't steal my brother!
あなたが…
あなたがミチコさんなのね
You are...
You're Miss Michiko, aren't you?!
マズい… もう１人
生み出してしまったのか
This is very bad.
Another one has been born!
早く逃げるんだ ヤサコ！
Run, quickly! Yasako!
（幼少のイサコ）やめて！
Stop it!
お兄ちゃんと別れたくない！
I don't want to be separated from my brother!
I'll be with my brother forever!
私はお兄ちゃんと
ずっと一緒にいるの！
違う！
That's not true!
私はお兄ちゃんと
さよならをしたの！
I'd already said goodbye to my brother!
Amasawa,
天沢さん そこにいるのね？
you're there, aren't you?!
I understand...
分かった… 分かったの！
I understand now!
小此木…
Okonogi?
Listen.
聞いて！
天沢さんがミチコさんに願う前に
Before you made that wish to Miss Michiko,
your brother was already dead, Amasawa.
お兄さんは死んでいたの
You didn't make your brother die!
お兄さんを死なせたのは
あなたじゃない
The one who's there with you is...
そこにいるのは…
No.
（ミチコ）ダメ…
お兄ちゃんは ずっと私のものなの
My brother will always be mine!
I hate you!
あんたなんか嫌い！
I understand now.
分かったの
You didn't give birth to Miss Michiko by yourself.
ミチコさんは天沢さん一人が
生み出したんじゃない
No!
イヤ！
Another person
（ヤサコ）もう１人いたの
ミチコさんを生み出した人が
helped you give birth to Miss Michiko.
And that person was...
それは…
Stop it!
やめて！
Me,
この私 小此木優子よ！
Yuko Okonogi!
My kiss interfered with your goodbyes.
（ヤサコ）
私のキスが あなたたちの別れを
邪魔してしまった
Michiko was born from my kiss and your anguish.
ミチコは私のキスと
あなたの苦しみの子供
Amasawa,
天沢さん 戻ってくるのよ
you gotta come back.
You should've left this Space already!
もう その空間とは
さよならをしたはずなんだから！
I won't allow it.
（ミチコ）そんなの許さない！
Run!
走って！
The link... is coming back!
（オバちゃん）
リンクが戻ってくるわ
Amasawa!
天沢さん！　そうよ こっちよ
Right,
this way!
Can you really abandon me like this?
（ミチコ）あなたは
本当に私を捨てられる？
It's not what you wish.
あなたは それを望んでない
Amasawa!
天沢さん！
You definitely can't part from me.
（ミチコ）
私と離れることなんてできない
You're the one who gave birth to me.
私を生み出したのはあなた
I'm the child you made to eat your anguish and sadness.
私はあなたの苦しみを 悲しみを
食べるために生み出した―
あなたの分身
It doesn't matter how many times you kill me,
何度 殺しても
私は何度でもよみがえる
I'll always be born again!
Because I'm your true soul.
だって 私は
あなたの本心なのだから
Stop! Stop already!
やめて… もうやめて！
You wanted to throw away your feelings for your brother,
（ミチコ）
あなたはお兄さんへの思いを捨てて
勝手に大人になろうとした
and become an adult without me.
I won't allow that.
そんなの私が許さない
天沢さん！
Amasawa!
ヤサコ！
Yasako!
（ミチコ）さあ 戻ってきなさい
Come on, come back.
こっちは とても心地いいわ
This place feels so good.
お兄さんも ここにいる
ここでは大人になる必要はない
Your brother is also here.
You don't need to become an adult here.
You can keep your sweet and lonely feelings for all time.
いつまでも
甘くて切ない気持ちでいられる
ずっと子供のままでいていいのよ
You can be a child forever.
勇子…
Yuko.
いけない ダメ！
It's no good...
No!
そっちへ行ってはダメ！
天沢さん！
You don't have to go there!
Amasawa!
（幼少のイサコ）髪の毛 結んで
Tie my hair!
天沢さん… うっ！
Amasawa...
ヤサコ もうやめて！
Yasako, stop now!
待って！
Wait!
これ以上は危険じゃ！
（オバちゃん）止めるぞ
Beyond this point, it's dangerous!
We gotta stop her.
ダメだ！
（オバちゃん）ハッ…
No!
ヤサコに任せるんだ
Let Yasako do it.
（ミチコ）
ここにいれば なんにもいらない
In this place,
you don't need anything.
大人になるための
痛みも苦しみも…
Neither the pain, nor the anguish
of becoming an adult.
天沢さんのバカ！
Stupid Amasawa...
それでも天沢勇子なの？
Do you deserve the name of Yuko Amasawa?
あの勇ましい天沢さんなら
戻ってこられるはずよ！
That courageous Amasawa
would be able to come back.
勇子のユウは…
勇ましいのユウ！
The "Yu" in Yuko is
the one from "courageous"!
やめて
Stop it!
痛い…
It hurts.
勇ましい…
You're courageous...
あなたは痛みを恐れない
勇ましい女の子
You don't fear the pain.
You're a "courageous girl."
だから イサコ！
So Isako...
戻ってきなさい！　イサコ！
come back!
Isako!
ヤサコ？
Yasako...
ダメ ダメよ！
No! No!
わあっ…
やめて 何をするの？
Stop!
What are you doing?
行くんだ 勇子！
Go, Yuko!
お兄ちゃん
Brother...
これで 本当のさよならだ
This is
our true goodbye.
（ミチコ）待って 行ってはダメ…
Wait...
You don't have to go.
That way, there's nothing but pain and anguish!
そっちには
痛みと苦しみしかないの
（イサコ）だから…
That's why...
だから行かなければならないの
That's why I have to go.
私は これから
あなたたちなしでも―
Because from now on,
I have to carry on living
自分一人で
生きていかなくてはならないから
by myself without you.
（ミチコ）やめて 私の勇子
Wait, my Yuko.
Don't abandon me, Yuko.
私を捨てないで 勇子！
（ヤサコ）生きなさい 勇子
Go, Yuko!
（ヤサコ･イサコ）
痛みを感じる方向に出口がある！
In the direction where you feel the pain, there's an exit!
（イサコ）
あなたの夢につながっていたのね
So it was connected to your dream.
（ヤサコ）うん
いつも不思議に思ってた
Yup,
I always thought it was mysterious.
私の心の世界は
The world inside my heart...
ずっと あなたの心の世界に
つながってた
has always been connected to the world inside your heart.
I did
私 あなたのことが嫌いだった
hate you.
でも分かったの
なぜ嫌いだったのか
But now I know.
I know why I hated you.
ずっと怖かった
I was afraid.
誰かと心がつながることが
怖かった
I was afraid to open my heart to someone.
But I'm not afraid anymore.
でも もう怖くない
見失っても
必ず道は どこかにある
Even if I lose sight of it,
there's always a path somewhere.
人は細い道でつながってる
People are connected through narrow paths.
時々 見失うけど
Even if sometimes they lose sight of them...
でも きっと つながっている
There's no doubt they're connected.
おかえり イサコ
Welcome back, Isako.
ただいま ヤサコ
I'm back, Yasako.
kono michi wo susunda nara
If I follow this path,
itsuka mata kimi ni
perhaps I'll meet you
We failed our last independent research project in elementary school.
（ハラケン）
小学生 最後の自由研究
やり損なっちゃった
aeru darou
again someday.
Yeah, you're right.
（ヤサコ）あっ そうね
That's why I decided to stop right now.
（ハラケン）
だから 今 終わらせることにした
tooku tsuzuite iku toki no naka de
When I continue into the distance,
The research on Illegals.
イリーガルの研究
I wonder what Illegals really were?
（ハラケン）イリーガルって
なんだったんだろう？
kyou wo natsukashimu
I'll surely long
I always wondered about that...
ずっと考えてた
kitto kono bashyo de
for this place.
今までの
イリーガルは 全部
Whether maybe Illegals
were some sort of feeling.
何かの感情だったんじゃ
ないかって
kasuka ni mieru
I see them faintly
Like desire, or fear.
憧れとか 怖いとか
sora no kakera wo
and chase
もう会えなくなって
しまった誰かに―
Like when you wish to meet...
oi kake de
the sky's fragments.
会いたいとか
someone who has passed away.
そういう気持ちを
誰にも知られずに―
I wonder if Illegals
hikari to kage mo
Light and shadow
are nothing more than Nulls
消えていくはずの
気持ちを
あのヌルたちが
拾い上げていたとしたら
who picked up the various kinds of feelings
kokoro ni egaite
paint your heart
それがイリーガル
なんじゃないかって
that should've disappeared
without anyone knowing about them.
hashiru toki
when you run.
Maybe Kanna as well.
もしかして カンナちゃんも？
sono waratta kao ga yuuki wo kureru
Your smiling face
Yup.
うん 僕の心の中のカンナが
Maybe the Kanna inside my heart
came to find me by following the path of my heart.
心の道を通じて
会いにきたのかなって
nanigenai kotoba dake de
fills me with courage.
And if
もし ミチコさんも
イリーガルだったとしたら
Miss Michiko was also an Illegal,
kimi ga namida no hi wa
With just your careless words,
what could she have been...
なんだったんだろう？
tonde iku kara
you'll fly away
The feelings from when Amasawa and I gave birth to Miss Michiko.
私と天沢さんが
ミチコさんを生んだ―
itsudemo
on tearful days.
あのときの気持ち
donna toki mo
At any time, at any moment...
Lonely, sad...
切なくて悲しくて それに…
and...
michi wa tsuzuiteru
And the path goes on...
A bit painful.
ちょっと苦しい
I wonder if those feelings might be...
その気持ちって もしかして…
first love?
初恋かな？
（ヤサコ）えっ？
（ヤサコ）うん
そうかもしれないわね
That could be the case.
The Next Spring
We became middle school students.
私たちは
中学生になりました
In the end, Amasawa moved back to Kanazawa without saying anything.
天沢さんは
結局 何も言わずに
金沢(かなざわ)に
行ってしまいました
Yes, hello?
はい もしもし？
Amasawa?
天沢さん？
You know, I still don't know...
ねえ 私まだ
どっちだか分からないの
Did we
私たちって
友達になれたのかな？
become friends... or not?
I already told you.
（イサコ）言っただろ
I don't really know what it means "to be friends."
私は友達というものは
よく分からないんだ
Ah...
（ヤサコ）そう
But you...
（イサコ）
でも お前は そうだな…
Yup, you were a companion who got lost on the same path as me,
同じ道を迷って
同じ道を目指した仲間だ
and you looked for the same path I did.
But we're companions only when we're looking for the same path.
（イサコ）でも仲間なのは
同じ道を目指してるときだけだ
A person like me, if I always stay with other people,
私みたいな人間は
いつまでも他人と一緒にいては
I lose sight of my own path.
自分の道が見えなくなってしまう
Maybe you're right.
（ヤサコ）そうかもね
Let's meet again.
また会おう 同じ道を迷ったときに
When we get lost again.
Yes.
Until that time,
それまでは さよならだ
goodbye.
Yes.
I'm Isako.
私はイサコ
You're the one who gave me my name.
名付け親は あんただ
（京子(きょうこ)）んっ？
Densuke...
デンスケ？
Kyoko, did you see him?
京子 見えた？